<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post on Aruna Mahajan&#39;s Poems</title>
    <link>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post on Aruna Mahajan&#39;s Poems</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 05:47:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Nari Shakti</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/nari-shakti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 05:47:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/nari-shakti/</guid>
      <description>In the country I was born, There woman&amp;#39;s power is adorned. Laxmi, the bestower of wealth. Durga, the vanquisher of enemies. Sarasvati, the patron of knowledge. And Siddhi-Datri, the angel of harmony. Be exalted the whole year, not just for a day, Maintain your esteem, that&amp;#39;s all I pray. Don&amp;#39;t vilify or trample others to rise, Trust your ability, and soar the skiess. Be honest, be creative, be loved. And live with your head held high.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covid 19</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>समय समय पर धरती पर राक्षस जन्म लेते रहे हैं, मानव को बचाने प्रभु अवतरित होते रहे हैं। अवतार ले कर एक दिव्या शक्ति ने हमेशा मानव को उबारा है , इस बार राक्षस का जन्म covid 19 के रूप में हुआ है, यह राक्षस टेढा है ,गुप्त रूप से इसने पूरी धरती को घेरा है। इस बार प्रभु ने मनुष्य को ज़िम्मेदारी सौंपी है। खुद उठो, खुद को सम्भालो ,खुद की रक्षा करो । प्रभु बोले, सारा दिन किसी न किसी उलझन में रहते हो ,अब ज़रा आराम करो, दौड़ से बचो ,जमा किये खजाने का आनंद लो ,और जमा की रेस से बचो, जरूरत का हर सामान है ,ध्यान से देखो ,शांत हो कर देखो, दर के साये से बाहर आओ। जीवन है कृतज्ञ हो जाओ, स्वस्थ हो नतमस्तक हो जाओ, छत के नीचे हो ,आपदाओं से बचे हो, यह ख़ुशी अनुभव करो ,हाथ जोड़ लो। प्रभु ने समझाया, संयम से काम करो शांत बैठो तो मानव जीतेगा, अंतरात्मा का आनंद अनुभव किया ,मानवता को समझा तो मानव जीतेगा मनुष्य ने संतोष को जान लिया, तो मानव जीतेगा। मनुष्य ही भगवान् है उस से परे कुछ नहीं, थोड़े से समय में covid 19 से ज्ञान दे रहा हूँ, शांत बैठो अन्तःस्थित हो जाओ, राम ने जन्म ले कर रावण को मारा, कृष्णा ने अवतार ले कंस को मारा, माँदुर्गा ने रॉकजबीज को मारा, माँ काली ने चण्ड मुंड को संहारा। इस बार सिर्फ शांति, संयम और अंदर रहने का हथियार चाहिए, इसीलिए मानव को ही ज़िम्मेदार बनाया है, अंदर रहो ,अंदर झांको और covid 19 का संहार करो। रावण का जीवन नाभि कलश में था, covid 19 का जीवन लोगों के समूह में है इस को मारने का बाण केवल दूरियां हैं, इसे मार भगाया तो मिल कर दावत करेंगे, यह ज़िंदा रहा तो चेहरे भी न देख पाएंगे, इस के ज़हर को पहचानो ,प्रेम से परिवार में रहो। मानवता को जीवित रखो ,संतोष से नतमस्तक रहो, भगवान् का आशीर्वाद तुम्हारे साथ है, जीवन के इस अंतराल में आँखे खोलो, मानव की जीत निश्चित है।</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/pandemic/</guid>
      <description>The scare of COVID19 has brought everyone down to knees, whole world was flying high to reach the skies, To explore the moon, to reach the mars, to touch the Sun, there was no thought for the Planet Earth. Oceans polluted, ponds and rivers dried, Trees were cut, forest fires burnt like hearth, Animals ran around to save their lives, They lost their families and habitats, They cried silently before God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Woman, you are the power</title>
      <link>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/women-s-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adityam.github.io/aruna-poems/post/women-s-day/</guid>
      <description>Born in a country where women power has been worshipped. You are given strength as Durga, and demons were killed. As the Goddess Lakshmi finances were under your Hand. As Saraswati the arts and sciences were blessed. Not for a day but whole year, in different forms you are worshipped. Hold your head High, Keep your words sweet, respect your own being. Don&amp;#39;t criticize women, or crack jokes on them, Never step on others to rise higher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>